<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-03-06T12:10:47-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Omni Ops LLC</title><subtitle>We build practical applications using AI to solve everyday problems.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Infrastructure as Code Generator: Project Breakdown</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/iac/2023/03/06/infrastructure-as-code-generator-project-breakdown.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Infrastructure as Code Generator: Project Breakdown" /><published>2023-03-06T12:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-03-06T12:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/iac/2023/03/06/infrastructure-as-code-generator-project-breakdown</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/iac/2023/03/06/infrastructure-as-code-generator-project-breakdown.html">&lt;p&gt;This post discusses the Infrastructure as Code generator that we will be building. Our goal is to test out the capabilities of OpenAI’s Codex Model’s to generate Ansible Playbooks from configurations pulled from devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sections&quot;&gt;Sections&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why build a Infrasturcutre as Code Generator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Key Technologies in Use&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;End Goal of this Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-build-a-infrasturcutre-as-code-generator&quot;&gt;Why build a Infrasturcutre as Code Generator?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was a Network Administrator, I spent a lot of my time dedicated to projects focused around building Infrastructure as Code (IaC). This code consisted of Ansible Playbooks and DNA Center Plug and Play (DNAC PnP). This code focused on initial provisioning, auditing, and making changes to our network devices. 
The work, at its simplist consisted of taking current configurations of our devices, and translating that to Ansible or DNAC PnP scripts; easy enough right? However, a majority of my time was spent translating Cisco configurations to code. Exploring OpenAI and their Codex model series, this seems like a perfect pairing to use AI to help translate from a configuraiton to code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-problem&quot;&gt;The Problem&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generating Infrastructure as Code from current Infrastructure configurations is a tedious, time consuming act that is mainly the act of translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-solution&quot;&gt;The Solution&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build a application that can ingress current configurations for devices and output translated Infrastructure as Code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-technologies-in-use&quot;&gt;Key Technologies in Use&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key technologies that will be used to explore this solution will be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://platform.openai.com/docs/guides/code&quot;&gt;OpenAI’s Codex Model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ansible.com/&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pfsense.org/&quot;&gt;PfSense&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;codex-model&quot;&gt;Codex Model&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Codex model is a descendnt of GPT-3 from OpenAI which can translate natural language to code. Learn more about Codex from OpenAI &lt;a href=&quot;https://platform.openai.com/docs/guides/code&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-codex&quot;&gt;Why Codex?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenAI and their API’s have proven to be the industry leader in this technology. A notible company using GPT-3 is WARP (warp.dev insert link.). They are building a terminal that can take natural language and turn it into teminal commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;ansible&quot;&gt;Ansible&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ansible is a powerful platform where you build Ansible Playbooks written in YAML to automate your infrastructure changes. Learn more about Ansible and its uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ansible.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-ansible&quot;&gt;Why Ansible?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ansible is a populare technology in Infrastructure automation and is simple to use. The end user can develop and deploy playbooks from their personal computer with no additional infrasturcture needed to be built out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;pfsense&quot;&gt;PfSense&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PfSense is a free network firewall distribution based on FreeBSD. It is one of the leading open source firewall solutions that you can install and is easy to use and configure with their Web Portal GUI. Learn more about PfSense &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pfsense.org/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-pfsense&quot;&gt;Why PfSense?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use PfSense personally to secure my home network and love their product. Additionally, PfSense is widely available for no cost to many users making it a perfect platform to test out this concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;end-goal-of-this-project&quot;&gt;End Goal of this Project.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The end goal of this project is to test out OpenAI’s Codex Model in building Infrastructure as Code. We hope to discover the drawbacks and benefits of using AI as a translator to Ansible Playbooks. 
A succesfull end will be a simple applicaiton where a user can input their PfSense configuration with some basic instructions on what they want out, then they will get a ready to use Ansible Playbook that they can deploy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kevin Schrock</name></author><category term="projects" /><category term="iac" /><summary type="html">This post discusses the Infrastructure as Code generator that we will be building. Our goal is to test out the capabilities of OpenAI’s Codex Model’s to generate Ansible Playbooks from configurations pulled from devices.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Omni Ops LLC: Using AI to Enhance your Workflow and Projects</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/about/2023/03/01/omni-ops-llc-using-ai-to-enhance-your-workflow-and-projects.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Omni Ops LLC: Using AI to Enhance your Workflow and Projects" /><published>2023-03-01T12:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-03-01T12:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/about/2023/03/01/omni-ops-llc-using-ai-to-enhance-your-workflow-and-projects</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/about/2023/03/01/omni-ops-llc-using-ai-to-enhance-your-workflow-and-projects.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;omni-ops-llc---who-we-are-and-what-we-do&quot;&gt;Omni Ops LLC - Who We Are and What We Do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are Omni Ops! A company that is using the power of AI to enhance your workflow. With the recent blow-up of OpenAI and their product ChatGPT, the opportunities to harness AI in everyday applications have never been more prevalent. We at Omni Ops are dedicated to exploring the possibilities of using AI in everyday applications. This post is an introduction to who we are at Omni Ops and what we do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sections&quot;&gt;Sections&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who we are&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What we do&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our first project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-we-are&quot;&gt;Who we are&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Omni Ops was officially founded in 2023 after a long discussion over the power of OpenAI’s ChatGPT and what this means for the future. The founders, Kevin Schrock and Keenan Fraylick, both saw the potential in enhancing people’s workflow using AI. After this discussion, Kevin and Keenan decided to found a company dedicated to developing and testing potential products that use AI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;kevin-schrock&quot;&gt;Kevin Schrock&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;co-founder&quot;&gt;Co-Founder&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kevin graduated with a degree in Cybersecurity from Purdue University in 2020. After college, Kevin started working in the corporate world where he rotated through many departments and roles. His roles included the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Client Support Specialist&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ServiceNow Administrator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cybersecurity Analyst&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Network Administrator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all of these roles, Kevin noticed a common goal: automation. Every team had multiple goals, all pointing towards automating redundant tasks. After working on multiple automation projects and realizing the potential of using AI to help others automate and improve their workflows, Kevin co-founded Omni Ops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keenan-fraylick&quot;&gt;Keenan Fraylick&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;co-founder-1&quot;&gt;Co-Founder&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keenan graduated with a degree in Industrial Engineering from Purdue University in 2020, with a focus on Data Science and Lean studies. After college, Keenan has held roles in a variety of organizations, spanning various sectors. From his experiences, he has developed the following organizational skills:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Science and Analytics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Project Management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continuous Improvement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is also certified with the IISE as a Lean/Six Sigma Green Belt for his work in value-driven projects. In all of his roles and companies, Keenan has realized the importance of automation in the spirit of continuous improvement. He has also worked to implement data-driven solutions to a variety of cross-functional problems. Together with Kevin, Keenan co-founded Omni Ops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-we-do&quot;&gt;What we do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Omni Ops focuses on quick development of applications and fast testing to determine practical solutions of AI. We focus on creating monthly Proof of Concepts (POC) for AI applications to test out the viability of using AI for various situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;focus&quot;&gt;Focus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of our applications focus on improving the end-users’ lives through these pillars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time Saver - The application must save the end-user time by eliminating redundant or unimportant tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enhanced Workflow - The application must be seamlessly integrated with the end-user’s current workflow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automation - The application must automate redundant tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;commitment&quot;&gt;Commitment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Omni Ops, we believe in the power of open-source code and education. We are committed to the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open Source - All of our projects will be open source. We believe in full transparency of our applications and welcome community contributors to improve what we build.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Education - During the development lifecycle of all our products, we will post regular blog posts and YouTube videos discussing key development concepts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-project&quot;&gt;First Project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;infrastructure-as-code-generator&quot;&gt;Infrastructure as Code Generator&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first project will focus on helping system administrators build out Infrastructure as Code from their current environments. The application will focus on building Ansible Playbooks from configurations pulled from network equipment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kevin Schrock</name></author><category term="about" /><summary type="html">Omni Ops LLC - Who We Are and What We Do We are Omni Ops! A company that is using the power of AI to enhance your workflow. With the recent blow-up of OpenAI and their product ChatGPT, the opportunities to harness AI in everyday applications have never been more prevalent. We at Omni Ops are dedicated to exploring the possibilities of using AI in everyday applications. This post is an introduction to who we are at Omni Ops and what we do.</summary></entry></feed>